MUKAIL LASSISSI



lasmiksplendid@yahoo.com



4697421190



linkedin.com/in/mukail-lassissi-8488334b

Summary

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Qualified operations manager with over 9-years of leadership success in field exercise operations throughout the pacific and California. A true leader of character, intellect as well as organizational, interpersonal, and logistical skills. An effective, tactful, and diplomatic communicator with excellent analytical and presentation skills. Security clearance holder.

Experience



Logistics Manager



Officer

Served as the brigade Chemical, Biological, Radiological and Nuclear officer

- •Responsible for the development, training and evaluation of the CBRN program for 5,000 plus personnel
- •Served as the observer, controller, planner, trainer as well as supervisor during company training exercises
- Advised the Adjutant General Officer on the Army doctrine, planning, coordination and execution of individuals as well as collective training for CBRN operations
- •Managed a 50-60 personnel department as well as ensuring both their personal and professional development through the effective incorporation of the 5-S lean sigma
- ·Assessed priorities, planned and maintained routines as well as liaising with external agencies
- •Commanded a 50-60 of highly trained specialist personnel
- •Took responsibilities for the morale, welfare and training of subordinates
- Managed resources to achieve complex tasks within budget
- Investigated the causes of administrative problems



Solutions Architect

Jan 2018 - Present (5 years 3 months)

Communicated software architecture strategies to senior leadership and third-party business leaders

- •Participated in weekly meetings with client to discuss project direction and milestone achievement
- •Designed and implemented system security and data assurance
- •Managed and monitored installed systems for highest level of availability
- ·Managed use of various types of databases and configured, installed and upgraded new ones
- •Managed installation, upgrade and deployment projects and provided on-site direction for network engineers
- Assessed under-performing software and developed actionable improvements
- Customized in-development software to clients' current hardware environments, designing applications to span multiple systems

- •Monitored and tested application performance to identify potential bottlenecks, develop solutions and collaborate with developers on solution implementation
- •Mentored team, sharing skills and expertise and encouraged each member to bring forward ideas and suggestions for improvement
- •Created migration strategies to bridge development gaps between existing software architecture and future updates
- •Provided second and third-level technical support and troubleshooting to internal and external clients



air AIR - Architectuur Instituut Rotterdam

Jan 2016 - Present (7 years 3 months)

Repaired the aircraft electrical, avionics, radio frequency, propulsion, fuel, removed and replaced optical payload, and weapons systems to include the electrical, electronic, and mechanical systems associated with those systems; the GCS electrical and electronic systems; the GDT electrical, electronic, and radio frequency systems; takeoff and landing systems; and associated ground support equipment

- Supervised, inspected and performed maintenance functions, in UAS aviation field maintenance units (AVUM) and (AVIM)
- •Experienced RF tester; usage of equipment such as an oscilloscope, multimeters, for tuning and diagnosing, transmitting as well as receiving RF signals; and network analyzations
- •Fabricated structural parts, forming blocks, and shape metals in accordance with technical manuals as well as engineering guidance and approval
- •Performed a variety of quality structural repairs to the RQ-7B aircraft in accordance with technical manuals and engineering specifications

Amphenol Fiber Systems International

Jan 2016 - Jan 2019 (3 years 1 month)

Served as a lead for the production department

- •Managed a 4- personnel team in making sure they are efficient in their given tasks
- •Supervised the daily activities of the department and report back to the manager
- •Made sure schedules were maintained as well as customers deadlines
- •Actively engaged operators and constantly asked for feedbacks on how to improve department production

■ Combat Engineer

UNITED

Jan 2012 - Jan 2016 (4 years 1 month)

Managed a 3-man team by leading them, ensuring their safety and well-being, and making sure their weapon system and ammunitions were well managed, cared for and secured at all times during a field training exercise

- •Manage and ensure the readiness of 4 team members by conducting training classes and facilitating practice exercises that will ensure readiness for real-world operations
- •Communicate and coordinate maintenance scheduling with multiple agencies to ensure the readiness of up to 75 vehicles and other equipment assets
- •Developed a Package Tracker to assist in the processing of all administrative matters relating to the department, including awards, legal action, and career development packages; streamlining the process and ensuring all information was processed in a timely manner
- •Brief the managerial staff on all administrative matters pertaining to the department on a daily and weekly basis when required

•Volunteered 4 months at the Schofield Barracks Tax Center in order to assist both active-duty service members and retirees in filing their taxes; thereby, saving clients over \$4.5 million and received the Army's Certificate of Achievement for my excellence

Hurricane

Jan 2017 - Present (6 years 3 months)

Volunteered an entire semester of school during the disaster

- •Assisted in the transportation of foods and personnel to designated shelters
- •Provided both moral and emotional support to those afflicted by the hurricane
- Was awarded the Texas Humanitarian Service Ribbon for both exceptional and meritorious services Youth and Sports Fitness Coach######### Schofield Barracks HI# ########## 2013
- Conducted training, provided effective communication, answered questions from parents by holding parent-coach meeting at least 3-4 times a season towards a successful season
- •Held practices twice 2 a week and provided both moral and professional support to the youth athletes and the organization
- •Encouraged participation in all physical fitness activities both within the community and at respective schools
- •Sent out mass text messages to parents weekly to assess their kids, coach, the assistant coach, and the team-mom
- •Advised groups and individuals based on MOPS local policy as well as on Coach's individual experience with the MOPS model and vision

Heard Natural Science Museum####### McKinney TX 2012

- •Renovated, cleared, and cleaned up to 3 bird cages and wildlife pensially for the duration of volunteer time at the Heard
- •Cleaned, maintained wildlife areas for visitors and kids to prevent injury hazards and provide a safe and clean sanctuary for wildlife, campers, and volunteer personnel



Rotary International

Jan 2011 - Jan 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Renovated, cleaned streets of low-income earners, thereby clearing their sewage and drainage systems

- •Painted houses with no house or apartment numbers with the appropriate numbers
- •Cleaned and painted curbs, parking lots, and marking places and areas of emergency parking and those not designated for parking, thereby, saving the city over \$1.7 million in expense to develop and renovate these areas

Education



The University of Texas at Dallas

BS, SLP and Audiology



Collin College

Associate of Applied Science



Lekki Peninsula College

High School Diploma, Composite Risk Management



Skills

administration • army • budgeting • coaching • computer hardware • control • customer relations • database administration • design • directing